William Philipps

Location: London, UK

Mobile: +44795 631 7470

Open to remote work

in linkedin.com/in/willphilipps

Bē behance.net/willphilipps

will3philipps@gmail.com

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry

(2022-2023)

UI Design Programme certification; front-end development specialisation module

University of Edinburgh (2006-2010)

MA Hons, French and Italian Literature, Grade 2:1

SKILLS & TOOLS

UI and UX design Figma
Visual design Adobe XD
Branding and Photoshop
style guides Balsamiq

User research Copywriting

LANGUAGES

English native; Chinese, French and Italian limited working proficiency

INTERESTS

China experience

Lived and worked in China for six years; Mandarin speaker (HSK Level 5).

Language teaching

TESOL-qualified (Trinity College London) language teacher with two years experience.

ABOUT

UI/UX designer with a creative agency and tech education background.

Experienced at brand building, developing marketing campaigns and managing project delivery teams. Driven by aesthetic-led design that combines visuals and storytelling to create meaningful, effective work.

DESIGN PROJECTS

UI Design at CareerFoundry | London (2022-2023)

- Project-based online UI training program with a focus on design theory and tools, user experience, mobile app design and branding.
- Developed a portfolio including a responsive web app that lets users find quality food and drink venues nearby. Applied user-centric design principles, conducted research and testing, created personas, wireframes, interactive Figma prototypes and final product UI.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Account Director at Decoded | London (2019-2022)

- Marketed and managed delivery of digital learning programmes for global organisations, including UBS, Citibank and M&S.
- Developed brand guidelines and style guides, designed digital product marketing collateral, pitched and sold programmes at scale.

Strategist at Ogilvy | London & Beijing (2015-2019)

- Developed and executed marketing campaigns with cross-functional creative teams for clients including HSBC, British Airways and Twitter.
- Created award-winning British Airways' 'Flying the Nest' campaign in China (In2 SABRE award: advertising category).

Senior Editor at Urbanatomy Media | Beijing (2013-2015)

- Pitched and wrote features about arts, culture and lifestyle.
 Commissioned stories, edited magazine sections and copyedited submissions.
- Freelance work published by CNN, Slate and NewsChina; interviewed for TV and radio by CNN, BBC News and NPR.